<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Map2Frame on RoboSLAM Research</title>
    <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/tags/map2frame/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Map2Frame on RoboSLAM Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/tags/map2frame/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Feature Matching in BA-SLAM</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfmatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfmatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Active map-to-frame matching using SLAM condition scoring
is proposed for balancing time cost and accuracy in indirect, BA-SLAM.
Exploiting the submodularity property of pose optimization condition scoring
leads to an algorithm for deciding when to employ map-to-frame matching,
how many points to select, and how to prioritize the data association
to best benefit pose estimation outcomes. When applied to ORB-SLAM,
the algorithmic modification lowers run-time costs without impacting
localization performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map-Hash for Fast Local-Map Queries</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/maphash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/maphash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Long-term, large-area SLAM performance is best when it
is possible to match previously seen (but subsequently lost) map points
when they re-enter the field-of-view and are visible once more.
However, the time cost associated to matching against an ever increasing map
undermines real-time performance. We combine hashing and condition scoring
to arrive at a fast, bounded map-to-frame method we call &lt;em&gt;Map-Hash&lt;/em&gt;.
The value of &lt;em&gt;Map-Hash&lt;/em&gt; is shown on a modified ORB-SLAM implementation
relative to baseline ORB-SLAM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>