<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Researches on RoboSLAM Research</title>
    <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Researches on RoboSLAM Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SLAM Benchmarks: Closed Loop</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/clbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/clbench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; SLAM has long been envisioned as a means to assist
robots performing navigation tasks in unknown environments.  Yet,
benchmarking for SLAM most often uses open-loop data sets due for
reproducibility. Given that open-loop and closed-loop task performance
measures may not align, establishing a means to use SLAM in the
closed-loop for benchmarking is an important next step in algorithm
development. A ROS/Gazebo environment for SLAM benchmarking has been
created and open sourced. Several stereo visual-inertial implementations
are tested and compared. The Good Feature SLAM approach provides
competitive and robust closed-loop trajectory tracking in unknown
environments and without external absolute position measurements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Feature Matching in BA-SLAM</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfmatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfmatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Active map-to-frame matching using SLAM condition scoring
is proposed for balancing time cost and accuracy in indirect, BA-SLAM.
Exploiting the submodularity property of pose optimization condition scoring
leads to an algorithm for deciding when to employ map-to-frame matching,
how many points to select, and how to prioritize the data association
to best benefit pose estimation outcomes. When applied to ORB-SLAM,
the algorithmic modification lowers run-time costs without impacting
localization performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map-Hash for Fast Local-Map Queries</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/maphash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/maphash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Long-term, large-area SLAM performance is best when it
is possible to match previously seen (but subsequently lost) map points
when they re-enter the field-of-view and are visible once more.
However, the time cost associated to matching against an ever increasing map
undermines real-time performance. We combine hashing and condition scoring
to arrive at a fast, bounded map-to-frame method we call &lt;em&gt;Map-Hash&lt;/em&gt;.
The value of &lt;em&gt;Map-Hash&lt;/em&gt; is shown on a modified ORB-SLAM implementation
relative to baseline ORB-SLAM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing SLAM Benchmarks and Performance: Open Loop</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/benchmarking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/benchmarking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Systematic study of SLAM might benefit from a &lt;em&gt;design of
experiments&lt;/em&gt; type of benchmarking approach, as well as means to gauge
&lt;em&gt;best possible&lt;/em&gt; performance versus nominal performance. One way to
better understand SLAM systems is if a good set of benchmarks could be
established for quickly gauging general performance. Using decision
trees dominant SLAM benchmark and SLAM performance factors can be easily
determined. They can then inform algorithm development.
On the &lt;em&gt;best possible&lt;/em&gt; performance, we advocate for the use of &lt;em&gt;slo-mo&lt;/em&gt;
processing, which provides practically no per-frame time constraint on
the SLAM solver. The &lt;em&gt;slo-mo&lt;/em&gt; results should be upper bounds on SLAM
performance compared to the same method run with real-time constraints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Feature Selection in BA-SLAM</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfselect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/gfselect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; SLAM condition scoring as a means to derive robust camera pose
estimation methods for bundle-adjustment based SLAM are explored and shown
to improve pose accuracy by 30% while increasing runtime by only 2%.
The key idea is to perform &lt;em&gt;inlier selection&lt;/em&gt; of tracked feature points so
that the local pose optimization has strong conditioning. Combining this
geometric conditioning with appearance-based match scoring leads to the
stated outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Observability and Maximal Cardinality</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/oomc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/oomc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;
Uses the &lt;em&gt;good features&lt;/em&gt; for SLAM concept to propose a deterministic process
for inlier estimation that matches RANSAC performance while having a more
consistent time cost relative to RANSAC.&lt;br&gt;
Measurement selection and outlier rejection use feature condition scoring
and hypothesis testing. The outcomes suggest that randomized methods can be
superceded by bounded or fixed time-cost deterministic methods based on
feature point scoring.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Binary Feature Learning for Loop Closure</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/loopclose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/loopclose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;
Loop closure is an essential module in long-term SLAM, as detecting and recognizing
re-visited locations serves to bound localization drift and correct for
geometric map distortions. It also provides a mechanism to recover from
track loss. However, most methods employ offline learnt maps that cannot
be customized to the feature space of new environments. This work explores
a means to generate a loop closing map with online adaptive properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Features for SLAM</title>
      <link>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/goodfeats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivalab.github.io/RoboSLAM/public/research/goodfeats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; SLAM is an overdetermined online estimation problem whose
size grows with time, as new measurements are collected with each new
image.  Most &lt;em&gt;highly&lt;/em&gt; overdetermined problems can be converted to &lt;em&gt;smaller&lt;/em&gt;
overdetermined problems without suffering a loss in accuracy.  In that spirit,
good features for SLAM investigates the question: How can we determine what
visual features to keep or to remove to preserve accuracy?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>